calameo.com 2019-06-30

# Calaméo - Privacy

Calaméo is committed to providing you, visitors and clients of our site, complete and transparent information regarding the personal data that we collect and process. This Privacy Policy applies when you use our services either as a simple visitor to our site or as a registered user. 

## Introduction

Calaméo SAS, a company with a registered capital of €200,772, with head offices at 25, rue de Ponthieu – 75008 Paris, France, represented by its CEO, is responsible for your personal data in its capacity as a “data controller.” 

Calaméo undertakes to process the collected personal data in a lawful, fair and transparent manner pursuant to the French Data Protection act of 6 January 1978 (hereafter FDP) and the principles enacted by the European Parliament and Council of the European Union’s regulation (EU) 2016/679 of April 27, 2016 (hereafter GDPR), as well as to ensure its security and confidentiality. 

Your personal data shall only be used in the cases as provided for by law: 

  * The execution of a contract entered into with you, and/or 
  * Compliance with a legal obligation, and/or 
  * Your explicit consent to the use of your information, and/or 
  * The existence of a legitimate interest for the use of your information. 

This legitimate interest corresponds to the set of commercial or business reasons that justify the use of your information by Calaméo (to improve and customize the service’s features, to adapt and develop its commercial offers, to manage sales leads, to improve customer relations, to communicate with users and process their requests) on the condition that the pursuit of this interest does not disproportionately infringe upon your rights and freedoms. These legitimate interests relate to the development of the Calaméo platform and the publication and sharing of interactive documents with a growing public audience, across the world. 

Calaméo furthermore undertakes to put in place appropriate technical and organizational measures in order to ensure that only the personal data necessary to each specific processing purpose be processed. 

This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you simply and clearly regarding the following subjects: 

  * the personal information that we collect; 
  * the use of this information and purposes of processing; 
  * how long the information is retained; 
  * the privacy and security measures implemented to protect the information; 
  * data transfer; 
  * the right to access, rectify, object to, restrict and erase collected personal information and the right to data portability 

## What personal information do we collect on our site?

When you use our services, we collect personally identifiable information in several ways: 

### Personal data that we collect directly from you

When creating a BASIC account on Calaméo, the following information is collected and stored by Calaméo: your email address, a password and username that you choose, and whether the account is personal or professional. You may also choose to disclose your first name, last name, country, city, the URL of your website and language preference when you register or at any time after you register on Calaméo. 

If you sign up for one of Calaméo’s paid services within the context of a free trial, you must provide the email address associated with your Calaméo account, your first name, last name, country, phone number, and whether the account is personal or professional. You may also choose to disclose the URL of your website. 

If you sign up for a free trial as a professional, you must also disclose the name of your company, its size, industry and whether it is in the private or public sector. 

If you contact our Support service in order to obtain an answer to a question you have regarding the use of the Calaméo platform, we retain the question and its answer in our knowledge base so as to enrich it and improve future answers. 

### Personal data that we collect indirectly

If you wish to create your Calaméo account via a social network such as Facebook, LinkedIn or Google+, the following information is collection from your account and stored by Calaméo: your email address, your first name, last name, and public profile photo. 

### Personal data collected automatically when you use our services: our Cookie Policy

The personally identifiable information collected by Calaméo may be combined with operational data that we collect or that is collected by our processors using various technologies (cookies) while you browse our site. 

#### What is a cookie and what does it do?

The cookie is a record of information placed on your computer or mobile device in order to simplify, optimize and render more secure your navigation on our site. These cookies do not identify you personally, but they do allow their sender to recognize your device and to collect certain information regarding your navigation. They cannot contain viruses. 

#### What information is recorded when I browse?

The data collected in “log” files (IP address, browser type, browser language, pages visited) is information regarding site usage. This information is used to provide site features and functions (for example, the readership statistics provided to users). Although this data is not anonymized, it is always processed collectively. 

Marketing tracers (cookies) only collect information when you visit the “Pricing,” “Features” and “About” pages while logged into your Calaméo account. They do not collect any information regarding publications that you have viewed. 

These two sets of data are never combined for analysis. 

Cookies are valid for a maximum duration of 13 months. 

### Cookies used by Calaméo that are required for site function

Cookie  |  Owner  |  Description  |  Cookie duration   
---|---|---|---  
sid  |  Calaméo  |  These essential cookies store user session information for accessing your account and persistent information regarding your language and cookie preferences.  |  2 days   
token  |  Calaméo  |  |  2 days   
lang  |  Calaméo  |  |  1 year   
ckn  |  Calaméo  |  |  13 months   
  
### Third-party cookies that require your consent

Cookie  |  Owner  |  Description  |  Cookie duration   
---|---|---|---  
_gid  |  Google Analytics  |  Google Analytics cookies are used to collect anonymous information about how visitors use our website. We use this information to compile reports and to help us improve our website. The information collected is anonymous and includes the number of visitors to the website, what pages they visited and where they have come to the website from. More information is available [here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage). To opt out, click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  |  2 days   
_ga  |  Google Analytics  |  |  13 months   
_gat  |  Google Analytics  |  |  1 day   
_gads  |  Google DoubleClick  |  Calaméo uses Google DoubleClick to measure the effectiveness of our online marketing campaigns. These cookies are associated with the DoubleClick for Publishers service from Google. The purpose is to facilitate the display of advertisements on our site, for which the owner may earn some revenue. More information is available [here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662856). To opt out, click [here](https://adssettings.google.com/).  |  13 months   
IDE  |  Google DoubleClick  |  |  1 year   
CONSENT  |  Google DoubleClick  |  |  13 months   
NID  |  Google DoubleClick  |  |  6 months   
1P_JAR  |  Google DoubleClick  |  |  1 months   
_hssc  |  Hubspot  |  Calaméo uses Hubspot to analyze user behavior on our website and improve how we communicate our offers. These cookies collect information regarding how you interact with our site, when you visit and certain pages that you have visited. This information is shared with Hubspot. More information is available [here](https://legal.hubspot.com/cookie-policy).  |  1 day   
_hssrc  |  Hubspot  |  |  Session length   
_hstc  |  Hubspot  |  |  13 months   
_hubspotuk  |  Hubspot  |  |  13 months   
_zendesk_authenticated  |  Zendesk  |  These cookies allow Calaméo to communicate with you with a view to providing customer support during visits to our site. These cookies store session information that is shared with Zendesk. More information is available [here](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/cookie-policy/).  |  13 months   
_zendesk_session  |  Zendesk  |  |  Session length   
_zendesk_shared_session  |  Zendesk  |  |  6 hours   
_zendesk_cookie  |  Zendesk  |  |  13 months   
PREF  |  YouTube  |  YouTube uses these cookies to provide a personalized user experience and for analytics. More information is available [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/types).  |  13 months   
VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  |  YouTube  |  |   
YSC  |  YouTube  |  |   
vuid  |  Vimeo  |  Vimeo uses this cookie for analytics. More information is available [here](https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy).  |  13 months   
  
### Cookies used by the Calaméo viewer that are required for its function

Cookie  |  Owner  |  Description  |  Cookie duration   
---|---|---|---  
sid  |  Calaméo  |  These essential cookies store user session information for accessing your account and persistent information regarding your language and cookie preferences.  |  2 days   
token  |  Calaméo  |  |  2 days   
lang  |  Calaméo  |  |  1 year   
ckn  |  Calaméo  |  |  13 months   
  
### Third-party cookies used by the Calaméo viewer that require your consent

Cookie  |  Owner  |  Description  |  Cookie duration   
---|---|---|---  
_gid  |  Google Analytics  |  Google Analytics cookies are used to collect anonymous information about how visitors use our website. We use this information to compile reports and to help us improve our website. The information collected is anonymous and includes the number of visitors to the website, what pages they visited and where they have come to the website from. More information is available [here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage). To opt out, click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  |  2 days   
_ga  |  Google Analytics  |  |  13 months   
_gat  |  Google Analytics  |  |  1 day   
_gads  |  Google DoubleClick  |  Calaméo uses Google DoubleClick to measure the effectiveness of our online marketing campaigns. These cookies are associated with the DoubleClick for Publishers service from Google. The purpose is to facilitate the display of advertisements on our site, for which the owner may earn some revenue. More information is available [here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662856). To opt out, click [here](https://adssettings.google.com/).  |  13 months   
IDE  |  Google DoubleClick  |  |  1 year   
CONSENT  |  Google DoubleClick  |  |  13 months   
NID  |  Google DoubleClick  |  |  6 months   
1P_JAR  |  Google DoubleClick  |  |  1 months   
vuid  |  Vimeo  |  Vimeo uses this cookie for analytics. More information is available [here](https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy).  |  13 months   
  
#### Can I deactivate cookies? How?

The saving and storage of any cookie on your device is carried out pursuant to applicable law. 

If you do not click the “I accept” button on the cookie consent banner on the Calaméo website, cookies that are not necessary for the site to function will not be saved. 

You may also prevent cookies from being saved at any later point in time by configuring your browser according to the instructions available from [https://www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/). 

### Payment information

Payment information is required in order to use certain paid features of our website. 

This payment information is collected and processed by third-party payment processors. Provided you consent, the data may be stored by these processors in order to facilitate recurring and future payments. 

Only the order date and time, the billing address that you provide, your company name where appropriate, and the first six digits of your credit or debit card number are shared by these payment processors with Calaméo for our record-keeping purposes. We do not store any other payment information. 

### Minors’ personal data

**IF YOU ARE UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE, PLEASE DO NOT USE OR ACCESS CALAMEO IN ANY MANNER.**

The Calaméo service is not open to minors under the age of 13 and Calaméo collects no personally identifiable information regarding any person under the age of 13. If you are the parent or legal guardian of a minor under the age of 13 who has become a member of Calaméo, please contact us at [privacy@calameo.com](mailto:privacy@calameo.com) so that his/her account can be closed and the data erased. 

If a minor between the ages of 13 and 15 wishes to register on Calaméo, this registration will only be legal if consent is jointly granted by the minor in question and the holder(s) of parental authority over this minor. The holder(s) of parental authority must transmit photo identification and proof of their relationship with the minor. 

Above the age of 15, a minor may register independently on Calaméo and consent to the processing of his/her personal data. 

Minors have a broadened right to erase personal data collected during their minority. For more information, please contact us at [privacy@calameo.com](mailto:privacy@calameo.com). 

## How do we use your data and for what purposes?

We use the data that we collect to provide and improve our products and services, but also to communicate with you regarding our products, services and offers. 

We may use your personal information to provide customer support, to send you administrative messages (including updates concerning the optimal operation of the service and security notifications), and to respond to messages that you send us. 

We may also use this information to analyze the usage of our site and technical problems that may occur, to reproduce the data in order to ensure its backup, or to process transactions and send you information regarding those transactions. 

Calaméo uses operational information that we collect (such as publications and pages viewed, origin of visit and the date, time and duration of your browsing) to help create an optimal and secure user experience, and in order to improve our service by, for example, providing you with personalized advice. 

Calaméo relies on third-party processors, to whom certain personal information may be transferred, mainly in order to: produce statistics regarding site usage, ensure the backup of platform data, provide user support, process payments, send emails to users and display advertisements that may interest you based on your activity when browsing our site. 

Finally, Calaméo may use your information within the context of marketing and sales operations: 

  * If you have explicitly granted your consent, 
  * If you are already subscribed to one of our paid services and the sales operation concerns a product similar to the one you have already purchased from us, 
  * If you register for our service as part of your professional activity. 

In any case, you may exercise your right to be excluded from these sales and marketing operations by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link present in each message, by updating your preferences in your account Settings or by sending a request to [privacy@calameo.com](mailto:privacy@calameo.com). 

## How long is personal data retained?

Pursuant to the French Data Protection (FDP) act of 6 January 1978 and the European Regulation (GDPR) of 26 April 2016, the personally identifiable information collected by Calaméo is only retained for as long as is required for the purpose of its processing. 

Calaméo ensures that the conservation period is proportional to the purpose of processing for each category of data collected. 

### Summary table showing the conservation period for each data category

Type of data  |  Conservation period   
---|---  
Data relating to an active client   
Set of data relating to managing a user account  |  Throughout the entire duration of the contractual relation   
Data relating to an inactive client – after account deletion   
Contact and identification data  |  5 years after the contract’s end or last contact by the inactive client   
Data relating to the execution of the contract (invoices, orders, payments, customer support)  |  10 years after the contract’s end   
Data related to a sales lead   
Data relating to managing a sales lead  |  3 years following data collection by Calaméo or last contact from sales lead   
Data related to the exercising of a legal right   
Proof of identity when the right to access, to rectification or to register is exercised for a minor between the ages of 13 and 15  |  1 year   
Data relating to proof of identity when the right to object is exercised  |  3 years   
Data backup   
Backup of all data  |  Daily operation   
  
When justified by the data processor’s legitimate interest or compliance with a legal obligation, certain data may be retained beyond the period defined by the data processor in the form of temporary storage meeting specific requirements: limited access to the data, an independent medium not accessible via the production systems, access when necessary and clearly justified. In such cases, the conservation period will be equal to the legal requirement or to the establishment, exercise or defense of rights in court. 

## What privacy and security measures are implemented to protect personal data?

Calaméo takes the protection of your personal information seriously and has established security procedures with a view to safeguarding it from unauthorized access, use, disclosure or modification. We routinely evaluate our practices, review data security and conduct maintenance to ensure the integrity of the personal information that we collect and store. 

Access to personal information by Calaméo employees and third-party processors is protected and restricted to appropriate use. 

In the event that Calaméo becomes aware of a security breach, we will notify you electronically in a timely manner, except where required not to by law, so that you can take any necessary protection measures. 

When paid by credit or debit card, transactions take place between you and our payment processing partners, recognized for their reliability in online transactions. Transactions are encrypted (SSL encryption process). 

In all of secure zones where the Calaméo URL begins with https:// (where “s” stands for “secured”), the data is encrypted and protected before being sent via the Internet. 

## Does calameo transfer data to third parties?

Calaméo does not transfer any data to third parties for commercial purposes, but rather only to help us improve our services, including processing orders, data storage and backup, security, customer support, data analysis and the improvement of our marketing. 

Calaméo only transfers personally identifiable information to other countries after having ensured the existence of appropriate guarantees that this data will be processed in accordance with our Privacy Policy and not used for other purposes. 

### Table of data transfers

Recipient  |  Type of data  |  Processing purpose  |  Transfer outside of EU  |  Safeguards   
---|---|---|---|---  
Content delivery network  |  Profile photo  |  Registration  |  Yes  |  Privacy Shield   
Customer service  |  ticketing  |  Data for support purposes Customer support  |  Yes  |  Privacy Shield ; standard clauses   
Marketing services  |  Sales prospection data  |  Management of sales leads  |  Yes  |  Privacy Shield ; standard clauses   
Payment processors  |  Billing address, method of payment, first 6 digits of credit/debit card used  |  Paid subscriptions  |  Yes  |  Standard clauses   
Content delivery network  |  Site use data  |  Measurement of Calaméo website usage  |  Yes  |  Privacy Shield ; standard clauses   
Messaging service  |  Email address, last name, first name, language, country, professional status, last log-in to site  |  Sending of Calaméo’s marketing communications and commercial offers  |  Yes  |  Privacy Shield ; standard clauses   
  
## Your right to data portability and right to access, modify, object to, restrict and erase collected personal information

Pursuant to the French Data Protection (FDP) act no. 78-17 of 6 January 1978 and the European Regulation (GDPR) of 26 April 2016, you have the right to access, rectify, erase, restrict and object to data that concerns you, in addition to the right to request data portability. 

You may view, modify and delete the personal information available in your Calaméo account at any time by logging into the website and updating the “Account info” and “Profile info” sections under the “Settings” tab. 

You may choose to receive our newsletter and commercial offers by email when you register for a Calaméo account or any time thereafter. You may also unsubscribe by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link in any of our newsletters, or by logging into your account and updating your preferences in the “Notifications” setting under the “Settings” tab. 

You may also exercise your right to access, rectify, erase, object to or restrict your personal information, where there is a legitimate basis and where it does not conflict with the processing purposes, by sending a request by post to the following address: Calaméo – 25 rue de Ponthieu 75008 Paris – France, or by email to [privacy@calameo.com](mailto:privacy@calameo.com). We will respond to your request in a timely manner. 

Moreover, when the basis for automatic processing of personal data is consent or the execution of a contract, you may request the transfer of data held by Calaméo to another data processor. 

Users who were minors at the time that their personal data was collected may have them erased as soon as possible by simply contacting the data processor. 

Finally, any individual may make provisions for the exercise of the aforementioned rights after his/her death, within the scope of general guidelines registered with a trusted digital third party certified by the French Data Protection Authority (CNIL) or specific guidelines registered with the data processor. 

Please note that any request to access, rectify, erase or receive a copy of your personal information must be accompanied by proof of identity in order for us to respond. 

In the event that a request is refused, the user may lodge a complaint with the CNIL (3, place de Fontenoy – 75007 Paris – France). 

For any other questions concerning our Privacy Policy and the processing of your personal data, you can contact us at [privacy@calameo.com](mailto:privacy@calameo.com). 

For questions regarding the removal of personal information from a publication that has been published by a user on Calaméo, please consult our procedure [here](https://support.calameo.com/hc/articles/205481168).
